# Thomas J. Herzog

thomasJherzog@gmail.com | (408) 476 1944 | San Jose, CA | https://linkedin.com/in/thomasJherzog

#### **Technical Skills**

Javascript (ES6+), HTML5, CSS3, React, Redux, Next.js, GraphQL, Jest, Node, Express, MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQL, Git, Github, Docker, NPM/Yarn, Babel, Webpack, ESLint, PHP

## **Work Experience**

C0d3.com - Fullstack Software Engineer - San Jose, CA - Remote

Feb 2021 - Present

Open source online software engineering education platform built with Next.js, GraphQL, PostgreSQL.

- Full curriculum review, security audit, documenting issues, and implementing patches.
- Setup error reporting system to correctly report all errors from our AWS Lambda functions
- Mentored students and reviewed teammates pull requests.

Ingoneering - **Software Engineer** - Portland, OR - Remote

Nov 2020 - Dec 2020

Enhanced and maintained a custom-built internal ERP business tool built with vanilla JavaScript, HTML, PHP, CSS, MySQL transitioning to React, Xstate, Docker setup.

- Updated payroll reports to include extra breakdown of weekly reports
- Reviewed, documented and fixed issues with 'progress complete' feature not updating correctly.

## **Projects**

SPA/PWA - React, Redux, Material UI

https://github.com/tomrule007/orderguide

Fully responsive single page PWA converting excel sales reports into searchable web based dashboard. Created specifically for department managers of a regional grocery chain.

Chrome Extension - JavaScript. CSS

https://github.com/tomrule007/highlight-active-row

Enhances visibility of the currently selected table row. Speeds up the entry process and greatly reduces errors that lead to lost profitability. Created specifically for department managers of a regional grocery chain. Now publicly available on the chrome web store with over 50 users globally.

NPM Package - JavaScript

https://www.npmjs.com/package/pdf-template-parse

A JavaScript frontend cross-browser compatible "PDF parser w/ template engine" to convert pdf documents into organized data objects

### Education

BSc, Electrical Engineering - San Jose State University - San Jose, CA

2008-2011

Dean's Scholar: Spring 2010

#### About Me

After completing my college senior project, building the <u>SJSU ZEM house (zero-emissions)</u>, I spent one year living and working on a farm studying sustainable farming practices. After which I went on to become sole proprietor of an organic specialty crop farm focused on biological regenerative practices to sequester carbon and reduce greenhouse gases. After 6 years of successfully running the farming business I have shifted my focus towards building technology, understanding its integral role in a sustainable future.